<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>IKFF</title><link>https://ikff.net/</link><description>Recent content on IKFF</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 12:52:02 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ikff.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Certified Kettlebell Teacher Level 1</title><link>https://ikff.net/blog/ckt-level-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 11:18:56 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ikff.net/blog/ckt-level-1/</guid><description>Since 2008 IKFF has established the global standard for excellence in the development of Certified Kettlebell Trainers
Certified Kettlebell Trainer – CKT courses standardize safe and effective kettlebell exercise, and guides fitness professionals to excellence in the art and science of teaching kettlebells to the fitness-minded and sporting public.
The IKFF provides a holistic approach to health, fitness, performance and well-being that is based upon the blending of body and mind and is integrated with the 5 Pillars of the IKFF Kettlebell system</description></item><item><title>Certified Kettlebell Trainer Level 2</title><link>https://ikff.net/blog/ckt-level-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 11:18:32 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ikff.net/blog/ckt-level-2/</guid><description>CKT Level 2 takes a deeper dive into the coaching and practice of the 5 Pillars of the IKFF Kettlebell system as presented in CKT Level 1 and expands into the mastery of double kettlebell training.
The IKFF reverse-engineering model exemplifies the ability of CKT Level 2 trainers to skillfully break down even the most complex sequences of kettlebell movements into the component parts, thereby being able to model safe and effective lifting mechanics to their students (customers/clients).</description></item><item><title>Certified Movement Specialist</title><link>https://ikff.net/blog/certified-movement-specialist/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 11:17:17 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ikff.net/blog/certified-movement-specialist/</guid><description>In this CMS Mobility course I present the Big Ideas that are the focus of this class:
Breathing - Qigong Balance mechanics and interplay Coiling Core Vertical transfer Base and changing base Hip and low back fluidity Actual flow (not same as routines) These are the Big Ideas that we focus on in this 5 hour CMS course, and you will have “homework” practice and you will submit a presentation of competence to complete the Earning of your CMS.</description></item><item><title>CKT Recertification</title><link>https://ikff.net/blog/ckt-recertification/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 11:16:38 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ikff.net/blog/ckt-recertification/</guid><description>Founded by (Steve Cotter) in 2008, IKFF has worked tirelessly to promote safe, effective kettlebell and fitness training all around the world. Along with (Ken Blackburn) and our team of (master trainers), IKFF has established a Global standard for excellence in the development of certified kettlebell trainers.
The use of the kettlebell has grown immensely world-wide over the past decade, and the need for a high-level of professionalism among the certified kettlebell trainers must continue to match this growth.</description></item></channel></rss>