<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kettlebell on IKFF</title><link>https://ikff.net/tags/kettlebell/</link><description>Recent content in Kettlebell on IKFF</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 11:18:56 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ikff.net/tags/kettlebell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Certified Kettlebell Teacher Level 1</title><link>https://ikff.net/blog/ckt-level-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 11:18:56 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ikff.net/blog/ckt-level-1/</guid><description>Since 2008 IKFF has established the global standard for excellence in the development of Certified Kettlebell Trainers
Certified Kettlebell Trainer – CKT courses standardize safe and effective kettlebell exercise, and guides fitness professionals to excellence in the art and science of teaching kettlebells to the fitness-minded and sporting public.
The IKFF provides a holistic approach to health, fitness, performance and well-being that is based upon the blending of body and mind and is integrated with the 5 Pillars of the IKFF Kettlebell system</description></item><item><title>Certified Kettlebell Trainer Level 2</title><link>https://ikff.net/blog/ckt-level-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 11:18:32 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ikff.net/blog/ckt-level-2/</guid><description>CKT Level 2 takes a deeper dive into the coaching and practice of the 5 Pillars of the IKFF Kettlebell system as presented in CKT Level 1 and expands into the mastery of double kettlebell training.
The IKFF reverse-engineering model exemplifies the ability of CKT Level 2 trainers to skillfully break down even the most complex sequences of kettlebell movements into the component parts, thereby being able to model safe and effective lifting mechanics to their students (customers/clients).</description></item></channel></rss>